[ indistinct chatter ]
Our pasta this evening is squid ravioli in a lemongrass broth
with goat cheese profiteroles , and I also have an arugula Caesar salad .
For entrées this evening , I have swordfish meatloaf
with onion marmalade ,
rare-roasted partridge breast in raspberry coulis with a sorrel timbale .
And grilled free-range rabbit with herbed french fries .
Our pasta tonight is a squid ravioli in a lemongrass broth ,
and the fish tonight is grilled ...
[ woman ] With a double espresso .
God , I hate this place .
- It 's a chicks ' restaurant . - Why aren 't we at Dorsia ?
Because Bateman won 't give the maître d ' head .
[ chuckles ]
[ waiter ] If you 'd like to take a minute , I 'll be right back .
Is that Reed Robinson over there ?
Are you freebasing or what ? That 's not Robinson .
- Well , who is it , then ? - It 's Paul Allen .
That 's not Paul Allen .
Paul Allen 's on the other side of the room over there .
- Who 's he with ? - Some weasel from Kicker Peabody .
They don 't have a good bathroom to do coke in .
Are you sure that 's Paul Allen over there ?
Yes , McDoofus , I am .
He 's handling the Fisher account .
Lucky bastard .
Lucky Jew bastard .
Jesus , McDermott , what does that have to do with anything ?
I 've seen that bastard sitting in his office
talking on the phone to the CEO spinning a fuckin ' menorah .
Not a menorah . You spin a dreidel .
Oh , my God , Bateman ,
you want me to fry you up some fuckin ' potato pancakes ?
- Some latkes ? - No , just , uh ...
cool it with the anti-Semitic remarks .
Oh , I 'd forgotten . Bateman 's dating someone from the ACLU .
[ laughs ]
He 's the voice of reason . The boy next door .
Speaking of reasonable ...
Only $ 570 .
Not bad .
A little something for the purse .
[ McDermott ] Give her the $ 50 .
♪ I don 't care ' cause I 'm not there ♪
♪ And I don 't care if I 'm here tomorrow ♪
♪ Again and again I 've taken too much ♪
♪ Of the things that cost you too much ♪
♪ I used to think That the day would never come ♪
♪ I 'd see delight in the shade Of the morning sun ♪
♪ My morning sun is The drug that brings me near ♪
♪ To the childhood I lost Replaced by fear ♪
♪ I used to think that The day would never come ... ♪
Two Stoli on the rocks .
These aren 't good anymore .
It 's a cash bar .
That 'll be $ 25 .
You 're a fucking ugly bitch .
I want to stab you to death ,
then play around with your blood .
♪ They 're afraid of what they see ♪
♪ That 's the price that we all pay ♪
♪ Our valued destiny comes to nothing ♪
What can I get for you two ?
[ Patrick , narrating ] I live in the American Gardens building
on West 81st Street , on the 11th floor .
My name is Patrick Bateman .
I 'm 27 years old .
I believe in taking care of myself
and a balanced diet
and a rigorous exercise routine .
In the morning , if my face is a little puffy ,
I 'll put on an ice pack while doing my stomach crunches .
I can do 1,000 now .
After I remove the ice pack ,
I use a deep pore cleanser lotion .
In the shower , I use a water-activated gel cleanser ...
then a honey-almond body scrub ...
and on the face an exfoliating gel scrub .
Then I apply an herb mint facial mask ,
which I leave on for ten minutes while I prepare the rest of my routine .
I always use an aftershave lotion
with little or no alcohol ,
because alcohol dries your face out
and makes you look older .
Then moisturizer ,
then an anti-aging eye balm
followed by a final moisturizing protective lotion .
There is an idea of a Patrick Bateman .
Some kind of abstraction .
But there is no real me ,
only an entity , something illusory ,
and though I can hide my cold gaze
and you can shake my hand and feel flesh gripping yours ,
and maybe you can even sense
our lifestyles are probably comparable ,
I simply am not there .
[ rock music plays ]
♪ Ow ♪
♪ Mmm yeah ♪
♪ I said baby I just want you back ♪
♪ And I want you to stay ♪
♪ Oh yeah ♪
♪ I 'm walking on sunshine ♪
♪ Whoa oh ♪
Morning , Hamilton . Nice tan .
♪ I 'm walking on sunshine ♪
♪ Whoa oh ... ♪
Aerobics class , sorry . Any messages ?
Ricky Harrison has to cancel .
He didn 't say what he was canceling or why .
I occasionally box with Ricky at the Harvard Club . Anyone else ?
Spencer wants to meet for drinks at Flutie 's Pier 17 .
- When ? - After 6 : 00 .
Negative . Cancel it .
And what should I say ?
Just say no .
Just say no ?
Okay , Jean ,
I need reservations for three at Camols at 12 : 30 ,
and if not there , try Crayons , all right ?
Yes , sir .
Oh , wait , and I need reservations for two
at Arcadia at 8 : 00 on Thursday .
Something romantic ?
No ...
Silly .
Forget it , I 'll make them .
- No , I 'll do it . - No , no .
Be a doll and just get me a mineral water , okay ?
You look nice today .
Don 't wear that outfit again .
What ? I didn 't hear you .
I said , " Do not wear that outfit again . "
Wear a dress , a skirt or something .
You don 't like this , I take it ?
Come on , you 're prettier than that .
- Thanks , Patrick . - [ telephone rings ]
I 'm not here .
And high heels . I like high heels .
[ contestant on Jeopardy ! ] Feathered friends for 600 .
[ Alex Trebek ] During courtship the male frigate bird
inflates to enormous size the red pouch found here ...
♪ She 's a craze you 'd endorse ♪
♪ She 's a powerful force ♪
♪ You 're obliged to conform ♪
♪ When there 's no other course ♪
♪ She used to look good to me ♪
♪ But now I find her ♪
♪ Simply irresistible ♪
[ woman ] Thousands of roses ,
and lots of chocolate truffles ,
Godiva , and oysters in a half shell ...
[ Patrick , narrating ] I 'm trying to listen to the new Robert Palmer tape ,
but Evelyn , my supposed fiancée ,
keeps buzzing in my ear .
Annie Leibovitz . We 'll get Annie Leibovitz .
And we 'll have to get someone to videotape .
Patrick , we should do it .
Do what ?
Get married . Have a wedding .
No , I can 't take the time off work .
Your father practically owns the company . You can do anything you like , silly .
I don 't want to talk about it .
You hate that job anyway .
I don 't see why you just don 't quit .
Because I want to fit in .
♪ Simply irresistible ♪
Williams party .
[ Patrick , narrating ] I 'm on the verge of tears
by the time we arrive at Espace
since I 'm positive we won 't have a decent table ,
but we do ,
and relief washes over me in an awesome wave .
Patrick , this is my cousin Vanden and her boyfriend , Stash .
They 're both artists .
- The menu is in Braille . - I see you 've met everyone .
You look awesome .
[ Evelyn laughing ]
Okay , okay , all right .
[ Patrick , narrating ] I 'm fairly certain that Timothy Bryce
and Evelyn are having an affair .
Timothy is the only interesting person I know .
I 'm almost completely indifferent
as to whether Evelyn knows I 'm having an affair
with Courtney Rawlinson , her closest friend .
Courtney is almost perfect-looking .
She 's usually operating on one or more psychiatric drugs .
Tonight , I believe it 's Xanax .
More disturbing than her drug use , though ,
is the fact that she 's engaged to Luis Carruthers ,
the biggest doofus in the business .
Tell me , Stash ,
do you think Soho is becoming too commercial ?
Yes , I read that .
Oh , who gives a rat 's ass ?
Hey , that affects us .
Oh .
Well , what about the massacres in Sri Lanka , honey ?
Doesn 't that affect us , too ?
I mean , do you know anything about Sri Lanka ?
How , like , the Sikhs are killing , like , tons of Israelis over there ?
Come on , Bryce .
There are a lot more important problems than Sri Lanka to worry about .
Like what ?
Well , we have to end apartheid for one ,
and slow down the nuclear arms race ,
stop terrorism and world hunger .
We have to provide food and shelter for the homeless
and oppose racial discrimination
and promote civil rights
while also promoting equal rights for women .
We have to encourage a return
to traditional moral values .
Most importantly ,
we have to promote general social concern
and less materialism in young people .
[ coughs ]
Patrick ...
how thoughtful of you .
[ beeps ]
Hello .
[ police siren ]
Bleach-ee ? Are you trying to say " bleaching ? "
- Bleach-ee . Oh , my God . Two things . - [ speaking Chinese ]
One , you can 't bleach a Cerruti . Out of the question .
Two , I can only get these sheets in Santa Fe .
These are very expensive sheets and I really need them clean .
If you don 't shut your fucking mouth ...
- [ speaking Chinese ] - ... I will kill you .
I have a lunch meeting at Hubert 's in 20 minutes with Ronald Harrison ,
and I need those sheets clean by this afternoon .
Listen , I cannot understand you !
This is crazy . You 're a fool .
I can 't cope with this . Stupid bitchee !
Understand ?
Patrick ?
Hi , Patrick . I thought that was you .
Hello , missus .
Isn 't it ridiculous coming all the way up here ,
but they really are the best .
Then why can 't they get these stains out ?
I mean , can you talk to these people or something ?
I 'm not getting anywhere .
Oh , what are those ?
Oh , well , it 's cranberry juice . Cranapple .
Really ?
Listen , if you could talk to them ,
I would really appreciate it . I 'm really late .
I have a lunch appointment at Hubert 's in 15 minutes .
Hubert 's , that moved uptown , right ?
Well , oh , boy , listen , I 've gotta go .
Thank you , Victoria .
Maybe we could do lunch one day next week ?
I don 't know , Victoria . I 'm at work all the time .
What about a Saturday ?
- Next Saturday ? - Sure .
Can 't , I 'm afraid . I have a matinee of Les Mis .
I really got to go ...
I 'll — Christ . I 'll call you .
Okay . Do .
Listen , you 're dating Luis . He 's in Arizona .
You 're fucking me , and we haven 't made plans .
What could you possibly be up to tonight ?
Stop it . I 'm ...
On a lot of lithium ?
Waiting for Luis to call me .
He said he 'd call tonight .
Pumpkin ...
Pumpkin , you 're dating an asshole .
Mm-hmm .
Pumpkin , you 're dating the biggest dickweed in New York .
Pumpkin , you 're dating a tumbling , tumbling dickweed .
Patrick , stop calling me pumpkin , okay ?
I have to go .
- Courtney ! - Mmm ?
- Dinner . - I can 't !
I 'm thinking Dorsia .
Dorsia 's nice .
Wear something fabulous .
[ moaning on TV ]
[ man ] Dorsia .
Yes , I know it 's a little late ,
but is it possible to reserve a table for two
at 8 : 00 or 8 : 30 , perhaps ?
[ man laughing ]
[ continues laughing ]
♪ You think I 'm magical ... ♪
[ Courtney ] A facial at Elizabeth Arden , which was really relaxing ,
and then to the Pottery Barn ,
where I got this little silver muffin dish .
Is that Donald Trump 's car ?
God , Patrick , shut up .
You know , Courtney , you should take some more lithium or have a Diet Coke .
Some caffeine might get you out of this slump .
I just want a child .
Just two ...
perfect ...
children .
[ moans ]
Are we here ?
Yeah .
This is Dorsia ?
Yes , dear .
Courtney , you 're gonna have the peanut butter soup
with smoked duck and mashed squash .
New York Matinee called it " A playful but mysterious little dish . "
You 'll love it .
And then the red snapper with violets and pine nuts .
I think that would follow nicely .
Mmm .
Thanks , Patrick .
[ pianist playing ]
Patrick , thanks so much for looking after Courtney .
Dorsia , how impressive .
How on earth did you get a reservation there ?
Lucky , I guess .
That 's a wonderful suit .
Don 't tell me , don 't tell me , let me guess .
Mm ...
Valentino couture .
Uh-huh .
It looks so soft .
Your compliment was sufficient , Luis .
Hello , Halberstram . Nice tie .
How the hell are ya ?
[ Patrick , narrating ] Allen has mistaken me for this dickhead Marcus Halberstram .
It seems logical because Marcus also works at P P and , in fact ,
does the same exact thing I do .
He also has a penchant for Valentino suits
and Oliver Peoples glasses .
Marcus and I even go to the same barber ,
although I have a slightly better haircut .
So how 's the ransom account going , Marcus ?
- It 's , uh , all right . - Really ?
That 's interesting . It 's not ... not great .
Oh , well , you know .
So how 's Cecilia ? She 's a great girl .
Oh , yeah . I 'm very lucky .
- Mm-hmm . - [ McDermott ] Hey , Allen !
Congratulations on the Fisher account .
Thank you , Baxter .
Listen , Paul . Squash ?
Call me .
- How about Friday ? - No can do .
I got an 8 : 30 res at Dorsia .
Great sea urchin ceviche .
[ whispering ] Dorsia on a Friday night ? How 'd he swing that ?
[ McDermott ] I think he 's lying .
Is that a gram ?
New card . What do you think ?
Whoa . Very nice .
Look at that .
Picked them up from the printer 's yesterday .
- Good coloring . - That 's bone .
And the lettering is something called Silian Rail .
It 's very cool , Bateman , but that 's nothing .
Look at this .
[ Bryce ] That is really nice .
Eggshell with Romalian type .
What do you think ?
Nice .
Jesus . That is really super .
How did a nitwit like you get so tasteful ?
[ Patrick , narrating ] I can 't believe that Bryce prefers Van Patten 's card
- to mine . - But wait .
You ain 't seen nothing yet .
Raised lettering , pale nimbus ...
white .
Impressive .
Very nice .
[ Bryce ] Mm .
Let 's see Paul Allen 's card .
[ Patrick , narrating ] Look at that subtle off-white coloring .
The tasteful thickness of it .
Oh , my God ...
it even has a watermark .
Is something wrong , Patrick ?
You 're sweating .
Hello .
[ gasps ]
Pat Bateman . You want some , uh , money ?
Some food ?
This what you need ?
I — I 'm hungry .
Yeah . Cold out , too , isn 't it ?
Why don 't you get a job ?
If you 're so hungry , why don 't you get a job ?
I — I lost my job .
Why ? You drinking ?
Is that why you lost it ?
Insider trading ? [ snickers ]
Just joking .
Listen , what 's your name ?
Al .
Hmm ? Speak up . Come on .
- Al . - Get a goddamn job , Al .
You got a negative attitude .
That 's what 's stopping you .
You gotta get your act together .
I 'll help you .
You are so kind , mister .
You 're kind . You 're a kind man .
- It 's okay . - I can tell .
Please , you gotta tell me what to do .
You gotta help me . I 'm so cold , I 'm hungry .
[ laughs ] You know how bad you smell ?
You reek of shit . Do you know that ?
[ laughs ] Al ...
I 'm sorry .
It 's just that ... I don 't know .
I don 't have anything in common with you .
[ dog whines ]
Oh , thank you , mister . Thank you .
I 'm cold out here .
You know what a fucking loser you are ?
- What ? - Hmm ?
[ dog whimpers ]
Oh ! Oh ...
[ dog barking ]
[ squeals ]
What beautiful skin you have , Mr. Bateman .
So fine , so smooth .
[ Patrick , narrating ] I have all the characteristics of a human being :
flesh , blood , skin , hair ,
but not a single clear identifiable emotion
except for greed and disgust .
Something horrible is happening inside of me ,
and I don 't know why .
My nightly blood lust has overflowed into my days .
I feel lethal , on the verge of frenzy .
I think my mask of sanity is about to slip .
♪ Deck the halls with boughs of holly ♪
♪ Fa la la la la la la la la ♪
♪ Tis the season to be jolly ♪
♪ Don we now our gay apparel ... ♪
Hey , McCoy , what do you say ?
Hey , Hamilton , have a holly , jolly Christmas .
Is Allen still handling the Fisher account ?
[ Hamilton ] Of course . Who else ?
Mistletoe alert . Merry X-mas , Patrick .
Merry X-mas , Harry .
- Merry Christmas . - You 're late , honey .
- No , I 'm not late . - Oh , yes , you are .
I 've been here the entire time , you just didn 't see me .
Say hello to Snowball .
Snowball says Merry Christmas , Patrick .
- What is it ? - [ grunting ]
It 's a little baby piggy-wiggy , isn 't it ?
It 's a Vietnamese potbellied pig .
They make darling pets . Don 't you ?
- Don 't you ? - [ pig squeals ]
Stop scowling , Patrick .
You 're such a Grinch .
What does Mr. Grinch want for Christmas ?
And don 't say breast implants again .
- Allen . - Marcus ! Merry Christmas .
How you been ? Workaholic , I suppose ?
I haven 't seen you in a while .
Hey , Hamilton !
We 're going to Nell 's . Limo 's out front .
We should have dinner .
Maybe you could bring , um ...
- Cecilia ? - Yes , Cecilia !
Oh , Cecilia would adore it .
Well , then let 's do it , Marcus .
- Great party . - Thanks .
Patrick , why is he calling you Marcus ?
Mistletoe alert .
♪ Repeat the sounding joy ♪
[ Mexican music playing ]
Marcus Halberstram for two at 7 : 00 .
[ Paul ] No , I want to know .
Okay , I came here for the cilantro crawfish gumbo , all right ?
Which is , after all , the only excuse one could have
for being in this restaurant , which is , by the way , almost completely empty .
- [ waiter ] I 'm very sorry , sir . - J B straight and a Corona .
- Would you like to hear — - Double Absolut martini .
Yes , sir .
Would you like to hear the specials ?
Not if you want to keep your spleen .
This is a real beehive of activity , Halberstram .
This place is hot . Very hot .
Listen , the mud soup and charcoal arugula are outrageous here .
Yeah , well , you 're late .
Hey , I 'm a child of divorce . Give me a break .
I see they 've omitted the pork loin with lime Jell-O .
We should 've gone to Dorsia .
I could have gotten us a table .
Nobody goes there anymore .
Is that Ivana Trump ?
Oh , jeez , Patrick — I mean , Marcus —
what are you thinking ?
Why would Ivana be at Texarkana ?
So , uh ...
wasn 't Rothschild originally handling the Fisher account ?
How 'd you get it ?
Well , I could tell you that , Halberstram ,
but then I 'd have to kill you .
[ laughing ]
I like to dissect girls .
Did you know I 'm utterly insane ?
Uh ... [ chuckles ]
Great tan , Marcus . Really impressive .
- Where do you tan ? - Salon .
I 've got a tanning bed at home . You should look into it .
And , uh ...
Cecilia , how is she ?
Where is she tonight ?
Cecilia is , uh — well , you know Cecilia .
I think she 's having dinner with , um ,
Evelyn Williams .
Evelyn .
Great ass .
Goes out with that loser Patrick Bateman . What a dork .
Another martini , Paul ?
You like Huey Lewis and the News ?
[ slurred ] They 're okay .
Their early work was a little too new wave for my taste .
But when Sports came out in ' 83 ,
I think they really came into their own ,
commercially and artistically .
The whole album has a clear , crisp sound
and a new sheen of consummate professionalism
that really gives the songs a big boost .
He 's been compared to Elvis Costello ,
but I think Huey has a far more bitter ,
cynical sense of humor .
- Hey , Halberstram . - Yes , Allen ?
Why are there copies of the Style section all over the place ?
Do you — Do you have a dog ?
A little chow or something ?
- [ laughs ] - No , Allen .
Is that a raincoat ?
Yes , it is .
In ' 87 , Huey released this ,
Fore ! , their most accomplished album .
I think their undisputed masterpiece is " Hip To Be Square . "
The song 's so catchy .
Most people probably don 't listen to the lyrics .
But they should , because it 's not just about the pleasures of conformity
and the importance of trends .
It 's also a personal statement about the band itself .
Hey , Paul !
[ screams ]
Try getting a reservation at Dorsia now ,
you fucking stupid bastard !
[ screaming ]
- You fucking bastard ! - ♪ You might think I 'm crazy ♪
♪ But I don 't even care ♪
♪ ' Cause I can tell what 's going on ♪
♪ It 's hip to be square ♪
♪ I like my bands in business suits ♪
♪ I watch them on TV ♪
♪ I 'm working out ' most everyday ♪
♪ And watching what I eat ♪
♪ They tell me that it 's good for me ♪
♪ But I don 't even care ♪
♪ I know that it 's crazy ♪
♪ I know that it 's nowhere ♪
♪ There is no denying that ♪
♪ It 's hip to be square ♪
[ Luis ] He was completely naked and he was standing
on the tables , with no clothes on —
Patrick ? Patrick !
Is that you ?
No , Luis , it 's not me . You 're mistaken .
This is my very good friend Patrick Bateman .
Where are you going ?
We 're going to Nell 's .
Gwendolyn 's father is buying it .
Ooh !
Where did you get that overnight bag ?
Jean Paul Gautier .
[ keys jingle ]
[ Patrick , narrating ] When I get to Paul Allen 's place
I use the keys I took from his pocket
before disposing of the body .
There is a moment of sheer panic
when I realize that Paul 's apartment overlooks the park
and it 's obviously more expensive than mine .
I calm myself and move into the bedroom ,
where I find his suitcase and start to pack .
It 's time for Paul to take a little trip .
Where to send the bastard ?
Dallas ?
Paris ? Singapore ?
London . I 'll send the ass to London .
[ beeps ]
[ imitating Paul ] Hi , this is Paul .
I 've been called away to London for a few days .
Meredith , I 'll call you when I get back .
Hasta la vista , baby .
[ beeps ]
♪ Lady in red ♪
♪ Is dancing with me ♪
♪ Cheek to cheek ♪
♪ There 's nobody here ♪
What is it ?
Patrick ?
Yes , Jean ?
There 's a Mr. Donald Kimball here to see you .
Who ?
Detective Donald Kimball .
Tell him I 'm at lunch .
Patrick , it 's only 10 : 30 . I think he knows you 're here .
Send him in , I guess .
Now , John , you 've gotta wear clothes in proportion to your physique .
There are definite dos and don 'ts , good buddy ,
of wearing a bold-striped shirt .
A bold-striped shirt calls for solid colored
or discretely patterned suits and ties .
Yes , always tip the stylist 15 % .
Listen , John , I 've got to go . T. Boone Pickens just walked in .
Just joking .
No , don 't tip the owner of the salon .
Okay , John . Right ... got it .
Sorry about that .
No , I 'm sorry . I should 've made an appointment .
Was that anything important ?
Oh , that ? Just mulling over business problems ,
examining opportunities , exchanging rumors ,
spreading gossip .
Hi . I 'm Donald Kimball .
Hi , Pat Bateman . Nice to meet you .
Sorry to barge in on you like this .
I know how busy you guys can get .
So , what 's the , uh ...
topic of discussion ?
I 've been hired by Meredith Powell
to investigate the disappearance of Paul Allen .
I see , uh ...
Paul 's disappearance , yeah .
So it 's nothing that official .
I just have some basic questions about Paul Allen ,
- about yourself — - Coffee ?
No , I 'm okay .
- Apollinaris ? - No , I 'm okay .
[ beeps ]
Can you bring Mr. —
- Kimball . - Mr. Kimball a bottle of Apollin —
- No , really , I 'm okay . - It 's no problem .
So , what 's the topic of discussion ?
The disappearance of Paul Allen .
Right .
Well , I haven 't —
I haven 't heard anything about the disappearance or anything ,
not on Page Six at least .
I think his family wants this kept quiet .
Understandable . Lime ?
No , no , really , I 'm okay .
You sure ? I can always get you a lime .
Just some preliminary questions that I need for my own files , okay ?
Shoot .
- How old are you ? - 27 .
Where did you go to school ?
Harvard , then Harvard Business School .
Your address ?
The American Gardens building , West 81st Street .
Nice . Very nice .
Thanks .
What can you tell me about Paul Allen ?
I 'm at a loss .
He was part of that whole Yale thing .
- " Yale thing " ? - Yeah , Yale thing .
What do you mean , " Yale thing " ?
Well , I think for one that he was probably a closet homosexual
who did a lot of cocaine .
That " Yale thing . "
What kind of man was he ?
Besides the information you 've just given me .
I hope I 'm not being cross-examined here .
Do you feel like that ?
No , not really .
Where did Paul hang out ?
- Hang out ? - Yeah , you know , hang out .
Let me think .
The Newport , Harry 's ,
Flutie 's , Indochine ,
Nell 's , the Cornell Club ,
the New York Yacht Club .
He had a yacht ?
No , he just hung out there .
And where did he go to school ?
Don 't you know this ?
I just wanted to know if you know .
Before Yale , if I remember correctly , Saint Paul 's .
Listen , I just —
I just want to help .
I understand .
Do you have any witnesses or fingerprints ?
Well , there 's a message on his answering machine
that says he went to London .
Maybe he did , huh ?
- His girlfriend doesn 't think so . - But has anyone seen him in London ?
- Actually , yes . - Hmm .
But I 've had a hard time getting actual verification .
A Stephen Hughes said he saw him at a restaurant there .
But I checked it out and what happened is
he mistook a Hubert Ainsworth for Paul , so ...
Had his apartment been burglarized ?
No , actually it hadn 't .
Toiletries were missing , a suit was gone , so was some luggage . That 's it .
I mean , no one 's dealing with the homicide squad yet or anything , right ?
No , not yet . As I said , we 're not sure .
Basically , no one 's seen or heard anything .
So typical , isn 't it ?
It 's just strange .
One day someone 's walking around ,
going to work , alive , and then —
Nothing .
People just disappear .
The earth just opens up and swallows them .
Eerie .
Really eerie .
Listen , you 'll have to excuse me .
I have a lunch meeting with Cliff Huxtable at the Four Seasons in 20 minutes .
The Four Seasons ?
Isn 't that a little far uptown ?
I mean , aren 't you going to be late ?
No , there 's one down here .
- Oh , really ? I didn 't know that . - Yes . It 's very good .
Listen ,
if anything else occurs to you , any information —
Absolutely . I 'm 100 % with you .
Great , and ...
thanks for your time , Mr. Bateman .
- Bye-bye . - [ Jean ] Good-bye .
[ woman screaming on TV ]
[ chain saw buzzing ]
[ Patrick ] I haven 't seen you around here .
You just haven 't been looking .
Would you like to see my apartment ?
I 'm not supposed to .
Do you want to come to my apartment or not ?
I 'm not supposed to , but I can make an exception .
Do you take a credit card ?
I 'm joking .
Come on , get in .
I 'd like a girl , early twenties , blonde ,
who does couples . Couples .
And I really can 't stress blonde enough .
Blonde .
[ beeps ]
I 'm Paul .
My name 's Paul Allen .
You got that ?
You 're Christie .
You 're to respond only to Christie .
Is that clear ?
♪ If you don 't know me by now ♪
♪ If you don 't know me ♪
♪ You will never , never Never know me ... ♪
That 's a very fine Chardonnay you 're drinking .
I want you to clean your vagina .
♪ If you don 't know me by now ♪
No .
From behind . Get on your knees .
You have a very nice body .
[ chuckles ]
[ telephone rings ]
Hmm ?
Thank you . Send her up .
Christie , get out and dry off ,
choose a robe —
Not the Bijan —
And , uh ,
come and meet me and our guest in the living room for drinks .
You 've arrived ! How lovely .
Let me take your coat .
I 'm Paul .
How good of you to come .
Not quite blonde , are you ?
More dirty blonde .
I 'm gonna call you Sabrina .
I 'm Paul Allen .
So ...
don 't you want to know what I do ?
No .
No . Not really .
Well ...
I work on Wall Street .
At Pierce Pierce .
Have you heard of it ?
You have a really nice place here , Paul .
How much did you pay for it ?
Well , actually ,
that 's none of your business , Christie .
But I can assure you it certainly wasn 't cheap .
No . No smoking . Not in here .
Varda truffle ?
I don 't want you to get drunk , but , uh ...
that 's a very fine Chardonnay you 're not drinking .
♪ You know I love you But I just can 't take this ♪
Do you like Phil Collins ?
I 've been a big Genesis fan
ever since the release of their 1980 album ...
Duke .
Before that ...
I really didn 't understand any of their work .
It was too artsy , too intellectual .
It was on Duke where , uh ...
Phil Collins 's presence became more apparent .
I think Invisible Touch
is the group 's undisputed masterpiece .
[ instrumental plays ]
It 's an epic meditation
on intangibility .
At the same time , it deepens and enriches
the meaning of the preceding three albums .
Christie ...
take off the robe .
Listen to the brilliant ensemble playing
of Banks , Collins , and Rutherford .
You can practically hear every nuance of every instrument .
Sabrina , remove your dress .
In terms of lyrical craftsmanship ,
sheer songwriting ,
this album hits a new peak of professionalism .
Sabrina , why don 't you , uh , dance a little .
Take the lyrics to " Land Of Confusion . "
In this song , Phil Collins addresses the problems
of abusive political authority .
" In Too Deep " is the most moving pop song of the 1980s ...
about monogamy and commitment .
The song is extremely uplifting .
Their lyrics are as positive ...
affirmative
as , uh , anything I 've heard in rock .
Christie ...
get down on your knees so Sabrina can see your asshole .
Phil Collins 's solo career
seems to be more commercial ...
and therefore more satisfying in a narrower way .
Especially songs like " In The Air Tonight "
and , uh , " Against All Odds . "
Sabrina , don 't just stare at it . Eat it .
But I also think Phil Collins works best
within the confines of the group than as a solo artist .
And I stress the word " artist . "
[ plays upbeat piece ]
This is " Sussudio . "
A great , great song .
A personal favorite .
- Look at the camera . - ♪ There 's a girl that 's been on my mind ♪
♪ All the time ♪
♪ Su-Sussudio ♪
♪ Oh oh ♪
♪ Now , she don 't even know my name ♪
♪ But I think she likes me Just the same ♪
♪ Su-Sussudio ♪
♪ Whoa-oa ♪
♪ Oh , if she called me ♪
♪ I 'd be there ♪
♪ I 'd come running anywhere ♪
Christie , look at the camera .
♪ All my life ♪
♪ I feel so good if I just say the word ♪
♪ Su-Sussudio ♪
[ breathes deeply ]
Don 't touch the watch .
Can we go now ?
We 're not through yet .
If they have a good personality and they 're not great-looking ,
then who fuckin ' cares ?
Well , let 's just say , hypothetically , okay ,
what if they have a good personality ?
- [ chuckles ] - [ laughs ]
I know , I know ...
[ all ] There are no girls with good personalities .
A good personality consists of a chick with a little hard body
who 'll satisfy all sexual demands without being too slutty about things ,
and who will essentially keep her dumb fucking mouth shut .
The only girls with good personalities
who are smart or maybe funny
or halfway intelligent or talented ,
though God knows what the fuck that means ,
- are ugly chicks . - Absolutely .
And this is because they have to make up for how fucking unattractive they are .
Do you know what Ed Gein said about women ?
Ed Gein — Maître d ' at Canal Bar ?
No . Serial killer , Wisconsin , in the ' 50s .
- And what did Ed say ? - He said ,
" When I see a pretty girl walking down the street ,
I think two things .
One part of me wants to take her out and talk to her ,
be real nice and sweet and treat her right . "
And what did the other part of him think ?
[ chuckling ] What her head would look like on a stick .
[ laughs ]
Hi , guys .
I want to get your opinion on something .
It 's my business card .
I decided to get a new one , too .
Oh , that 's ...
Very nice , Luis .
Thank you .
[ foreboding music plays ]
Listen , what about dinner ?
Is that all you ever have to contribute , Van Patten ?
" What about fucking dinner ? "
Cheer up there , Bateman .
What 's the matter , no shiatsu this mornin ' ?
Touch me again like that , and you 'll draw back a stump .
- Hold on there , little buddy . - Excuse me .
[ humming ]
[ kiss ]
God . Patrick .
Why here ?
I 've seen you looking at me .
I 've noticed ...
your ...
hot body .
[ chuckles ]
[ chuckling ] Don 't be shy .
You can 't imagine how long I 've wanted this ,
ever since that Christmas party at Arizona 206 .
You know the one .
You were wearing that red-striped paisley Armani tie .
I want you .
I want you , too .
- Patrick ! - What is it ?
Where are you going ?
I 've gotta return some videotapes .
[ glass shattering ]
[ Luis ] Patrick !
[ man ] Okay ... Monday ? The 20th .
[ woman ] Monday ? That 's , uh ...
- Any Paul Allen ? - Reservation ... no .
- No reservation , but — - Kimball .
I 've been wanting to talk with you . Come into my office .
Jean , great jacket . Matsuda ?
Do you remember where you were the night of Paul 's disappearance ?
Which was on the 20th of December ?
God .
I guess I was probably returning videotapes .
I had a date with a girl named Veronica .
That 's not what I 've got .
What ?
That 's not the information I 've received .
Well , I — Wait .
What information have you received ?
Let me see .
Um ...
- you were with — - Well , I ... could be wrong .
When was the last time you were with Paul Allen ?
We 'd gone to a ...
new musical called ...
Oh , Africa , Brave Africa .
It was a laugh riot .
That was about it .
I think we had dinner at Orso 's .
No , Petal — No , Orso 's .
I hope I 've been informative . Long day . Bit scattered .
I 'm a little spent now , too .
But ...
how about lunch in a week or so ,
when I 've sorted out all this information .
Great . Yes , I 'd like that .
And ... if you could try and pin down where you were
the night of Paul Allen 's disappearance , it would make my job a lot easier .
Absolutely . I 'm with you on that one .
Huey Lewis and the News .
Great stuff .
I just bought it on my way here . You heard it ?
Never .
I mean , I don 't really like singers .
Not a big music fan , huh ?
No , I like music .
Just they 're ...
Huey 's too black-sounding for me .
To each his own .
So ...
uh , lunch next week ?
I 'll be there .
[ grunting ]
Will you call me before Easter ?
Maybe .
[ sighs ]
What are you doing tonight ?
Dinner at , uh , River Café .
Au Bar afterwards , maybe .
That 's nice .
I never knew you smoked .
You never noticed .
Listen ...
Patrick ...
can we talk ?
You look ...
marvelous .
There 's nothin ' to say .
You 're gonna marry Luis .
Isn 't that special ?
Patrick ...
Yes , Courtney ?
If I don 't see you before Easter ...
have a nice one , okay ?
You , too .
Patrick ?
Yeah ?
Nothing .
[ door opens and closes ]
[ indistinct chatter ]
There is this theory now — listen to me —
There 's this theory now that if you can catch the AIDS virus
through having sex with someone who 's infected , then you can catch anything .
Alzheimer 's , muscular dystrophy ,
hemophilia , leukemia , diabetes , dyslexia .
I 'm not sure , but I don 't think dyslexia 's a virus .
Who knows ? They don 't know that .
Prove it .
[ sniffs ]
[ coughs ]
- Oh , God ! - What ?
It 's a fucking milligram of sweetener .
I wanna get high off this , not sprinkle it on my fucking oatmeal .
It 's definitely weak , but I have a feeling if we do enough of it , we 'll be okay .
Can you keep it down ? I 'm trying to do drugs .
Fuck you !
Calm down . Do it anyway .
That 's right .
That is , if the fag in the next stall thinks it 's okay !
- Fuck you ! - Hey , fuck you !
Sorry , dude . Steroids .
Hunh ! Okay , let 's do it .
♪ I wanna know ♪
♪ What you 're thinking ♪
♪ There are some things you can 't hide ♪
♪ I wanna know ♪
♪ What you 're feeling ♪
♪ Tell me what 's on your mind ♪
Where did Craig go ?
Well , Gorbachev is downstairs .
McDermott went to sign a peace treaty between the United States and Russia .
He 's the one behind glasnost , you know .
He said he was in mergers and acquisitions .
You 're not confused , are you ?
No , not really .
[ woman ] Gorbachev is not downstairs .
Karen 's right . Gorbachev 's not downstairs .
He 's at Tunnel .
Ask me a question .
So , what do you do ?
I 'm into , uh ...
Oh , murders and executions , mostly .
Do you like it ?
Well , it depends .
Why ?
Well , most guys I know who work in mergers and acquisitions
really don 't like it .
So ...
where do you work out ?
You think I 'm dumb , don 't you ?
What ?
You think I 'm dumb . You think all models are dumb .
No .
I really don 't .
That 's okay . I don 't mind .
There 's something sweet about you .
[ car alarm blaring ]
[ knock on door ]
Doin ' the crossword ?
You need any help ?
Jean ?
Yes , Patrick ?
Would you like to accompany me to dinner ?
That is ...
if you 're not doing anything .
Um ... no .
No , I don 't have any plans .
Well ...
isn 't this a coincidence ?
Listen , where should we go ?
Anywhere you want .
Let 's not think about what I want .
How about anywhere you want ?
I don 't know , Patrick . I can 't make this decision .
[ chuckling ] Come on .
Where do you want to go ?
Anywhere you want . Just say it . I can get us in anywhere .
What about ...
Dorsia ?
So .
Dorsia is where Jean wants to go .
Oh , I don 't know .
No , we 'll go any — wherever you want to go .
Dorsia is fine .
[ dialing ]
[ ringing ]
Uh , Dorsia . Yes ?
Yeah , can you take two tonight at , oh , let 's say 9 : 00 ?
We 're totally booked .
Really ? That 's great .
No , I said we are totally booked .
Two at 9 : 00 ? Perfect .
See you then .
[ hangs up ]
Yeah ...
you 're ...
dressed okay .
You didn 't give a name .
They know me .
Why don 't you meet me at my place ?
At 7 : 00 ... for drinks .
[ chuckles ]
And , Jean ?
We 'll want to change before we go out .
Patrick , it 's so elegant .
What a wonderful view .
Jean ...
Sorbet ?
Thanks , Patrick . I 'd love some .
Do you want a bite ?
I 'm on a diet . But thank you .
You don 't need to lose any weight .
You 're kidding , right ?
You look great . Very fit .
[ chuckles ]
You can always be thinner ...
look better .
Well , maybe we shouldn 't go out to dinner .
I don 't want to ruin your willpower .
No , it 's all right .
I 'm not very good at controlling it anyway .
So , listen ...
what do you really want to do with your life ?
Just briefly . Summarize . And , uh ,
don 't tell me you enjoy working with children , okay ?
Well ...
I 'd like to travel and
maybe go back to school , but ...
I don 't really know .
I 'm at a point in my life where there seems to be
so many possibilities .
But , um , I don 't know . I 'm just so unsure .
Do you have a boyfriend ?
No , not really .
Interesting .
Are you seeing anyone ?
I mean , seriously ?
Maybe .
I don 't know .
Not really .
Jean ?
Do you feel ... fulfilled ?
I mean ...
in your life ?
I guess I do .
For a long time , I was too focused on my work .
But now I 've really begun to think about changing myself .
You know , developing and ...
growing .
Growing .
I 'm glad you said that .
Did you know that , uh ,
Ted Bundy 's first dog , a collie ,
was named Lassie ? [ laughs ]
Had you heard this ?
Who 's Ted Bundy ?
Forget it . [ sighs ]
What 's that ?
Duct tape .
I need it for , uh ...
taping something .
Patrick ?
Have you ever wanted to , uh ,
make someone happy ?
What ? No ! Put it in the carton !
Sorry .
Jean ?
What ?
Um ...
Make someone happy .
Have you ever wanted to ?
I 'm looking for , uh ...
I guess you could say I just want to have a meaningful relationship
with someone special .
Hmm .
[ telephone rings ]
[ machine picks up ]
[ Evelyn ] Patrick . Patrick . I know you 're there .
Pick up the phone , you bad boy .
What are you up to tonight ?
It 's me . Don 't try to hide .
I hope you 're not out there with some little number you picked up ,
because you 're mine , Mr. Bateman .
My boy next door .
Anyway , um , you never called me , and you said you would .
And I 'll leave a message for Jean about this , too , to remind you ,
but we 're having dinner with Melania and Taylor .
You know Melania . She went to Sweet Briar ,
and we 're meeting at the Cornell Club ,
so I 'll call you tomorrow morning , honey .
Oh . Sorry . I know you hate that .
[ chuckles ] Bye , Patrick .
Bye , Mr. Big Time CEO .
Bye-bye .
[ machine clicks off and beeps ]
Was that Evelyn ?
Are you still seeing her ?
I 'm sorry . I have no right to ask that .
Do you want me to go ?
Yeah .
I don 't think I can control myself .
I know I should go .
I know I have a tendency to get involved with unavailable men .
Uh ...
I mean ...
Do you want me to go ?
I think if you stay ...
something bad will happen .
I think I might hurt you .
You don 't want to get hurt , do you ?
No . No , I guess not .
I don 't want to get bruised .
You 're right .
I should go .
Oh . Don 't forget you have a lunch date tomorrow
with Donald Kimball at Smith Wollensky 's .
Thanks .
It slipped my mind completely .
[ footsteps receding ]
[ door opens , closes ]
So .
The night he disappeared .
Any new thoughts about what you did ?
Not sure , um —
I had a shower ...
and some sorbet .
I think you 're getting your dates mixed up .
But how ?
Where do you place ...
Paul that night ?
According to his datebook , and this was verified by his secretary ,
he had dinner with Marcus Halberstram .
- And ? - I questioned him .
- Marcus ? - Yes , and he denies it .
Though , at first , he couldn 't be sure .
- But he denied it . - Yes .
Well , does Marcus have an alibi ?
Yes .
He does ? You 're sure ?
I 've checked it out . It 's clean .
Now ...
where were you ?
Where was Marcus ?
He wasn 't with Paul Allen .
Who was he with ?
- He was at Atlantis ... - [ flipping pages ]
... with Craig McDermott ,
Frederick Dibble ,
Harry Newman , George Butner , and ...
you .
[ chuckles ] Oh , right , yeah . Of course .
He had wanted Paul Allen to come ,
but he had made plans ,
and I guess I had dinner with Victoria the following night .
Personally , I think the guy went a little nutso .
Split town for a while . Maybe he did go to London ,
sightseeing , drinking , whatever .
Anyway , I 'm pretty sure he 'll turn up sooner or later .
I mean , to think that one of his friends killed him
for no reason whatsoever would be too ridiculous .
Isn 't that right , Patrick ?
Christie , Christie .
I 'm not so sure about this .
I had to go to emergency after last time .
This won 't be anything like last time .
- I promise . - I don 't think so .
Just come in the limo and talk to me for a minute .
Driver 's here . You 're safe .
Nothing like last time . I promise .
All right .
So you 're looking great .
How 've you been ?
Well , I actually might need a little surgery after last time .
Really ?
My friend told me I should maybe even get a lawyer .
Lawyers are so complicated .
Don 't do that .
Here 's a check .
[ tears check off ]
[ Patrick whistles ]
[ Patrick whistles again ]
[ footsteps ]
Uh-uh .
Half now , half later .
[ door locks ]
Okay .
Your name 's Christie .
We 're meeting a friend of mine , Elizabeth .
She 'll be joining us in my new apartment shortly .
You 'll like her .
She 's a very nice girl .
You look really familiar .
Did you go to Dalton ?
I think I met you at the Surf Bar , didn 't I ?
With Spicey ?
Well , maybe not with Spicey , but definitely at Surf Bar .
You know , Surf Bar ?
Anyway , Surf Bar sucks now . It 's terrible .
Went to a birthday party there for Malcolm Forbes .
Oh , my God , please .
This is nicer than your other apartment .
Well , it 's not that nice .
[ pouring ]
Where did you two meet ?
[ Elizabeth ] Oh , God . We met at , um —
Oh , God , at the Kentucky Derby in ' 85 or ' 86 .
You were hanging out with that bimbo Allison Poole .
Hot number .
What do you mean ?
She was a hot number .
Get a platinum card , she 'd give you a blow job .
Listen , this girl worked in a tanning salon .
Need I say more ?
What do you do ?
She 's my ...
cousin .
Uh-huh .
She 's from ...
France .
[ Elizabeth ] Where 's your phone ? I 've gotta call Harley .
[ rings ]
Where do you summer ? Southampton ?
No .
Oh , God . It 's his machine .
Elizabeth , it 's 3 : 00 in the morning .
He 's a goddamn drug dealer . These are his peak hours .
- Don 't tell him you 're here . - Why would I ?
- [ answering machine beeps ] - This tastes weird .
Harley , it 's me . I need your services .
Translate that however you want .
I 'm at ...
- [ whispering ] You 're at Paul Allen 's . - Who ?
- Paul Allen . - I want the number , idiot .
Anyway , I 'm at Paul Normand 's , and I 'll try you again later ,
and if I don 't see you at Canal Bar tomorrow night ,
I 'm gonna sic my hair dresser on you .
Did you know that guy who disappeared ?
Didn 't he work at Pierce Pierce ? Was he a friend of yours ?
No .
Do you have any coke ?
Or Halcion ? Ooh , I would take a Halcion .
Listen . [ sighs ]
- I would just like to see ... - [ pouring ]
... the two of you
get it on .
[ Patrick chuckles ]
What 's wrong with that ?
It 's totally disease-free .
[ laughs ]
Patrick , you 're a lunatic .
Come on .
Don 't you find Christie attractive ?
Let 's not get lewd .
I 'm in no mood for a lewd conversation .
Come on .
I think it 'd be a turn-on .
Does he do this all the time ?
Christie , you 're not drinking your wine .
[ Patrick ] You 're telling me you 've never gotten it on with a girl ?
No .
I 'm not a lesbian .
Why would you think I would be into that ?
Well , you went to Sarah Lawrence for one thing .
Those are Sarah Lawrence guys , Patrick .
You 're making me feel weird .
[ Patrick ] Did you know ...
that Whitney Houston 's debut LP ,
called simply Whitney Houston ,
had four number one singles on it ?
Did you know that , Christie ?
You actually listen to Whitney Houston ?
You own a Whitney Houston CD ?
More than one ? [ giggles ]
Ooh !
It 's hard to choose a favorite among so many great tracks .
But " The Greatest Love Of All "
is one of the best , most powerful songs ever written
about self-preservation , dignity .
Its universal message crosses all boundaries
and instills one with the hope
it 's not too late to better ourselves .
Since , Elizabeth ,
it 's impossible in this world we live in
to empathize with others ,
we can always empathize with ourselves .
It 's an important message .
Crucial , really .
And it 's beautifully stated on the album .
[ passionate moaning ]
[ muffled screams ]
[ panting ]
[ Christie screams ]
[ chain saw revving ]
Not the face , you bitch !
Not the fuckin ' face , you piece of bitch trash !
[ screaming ]
[ chain saw roars ]
[ gasps frantically ]
[ crash ]
Aaah !
I want a firm commitment .
I think , um , Evelyn ,
that , uh , we 've lost touch .
Why ? What 's wrong ?
My need to engage in homicidal behavior
on a massive scale cannot be corrected ,
but I have no other way to fulfill my needs .
We need to talk .
Talk about what , Patrick ?
It 's over , Evelyn .
It 's all over .
Touchy , touchy .
I 'm sorry I brought up the wedding .
Let 's just avoid the issue , all right ?
Now , are we having coffee ?
I 'm fucking serious . It 's fucking over . Us .
This is no joke . Uh ...
I don 't think we should see each other anymore .
But your friends are my friends ,
and my friends are your friends .
I really don 't think it would work .
You have a little something —
I know that your friends are my friends ,
and , uh , and I thought about that .
You can have them .
You 're really serious , aren 't you ?
Yes , I am .
What about the past ?
- Our past ? - We never really shared one .
- You 're inhuman . - No , I 'm in touch with humanity .
Evelyn , I 'm sorry .
I just , uh ...
You 're not terribly important to me .
[ sobbing ] Oh , no .
No , no .
I know my behavior can be ...
erratic sometimes .
What do you want me to do ?
What is it that you want ?
If you really want to do something for me , then stop making this scene right now .
- Oh , God , I can 't believe this . - I 'm leaving .
I 've assessed the situation , and I 'm going .
Where are you going ?
Just leaving .
But where ?
I have to return some videotapes .
- [ cat meows ] - [ ATM beeps ]
Here , kitty , kitty .
[ ATM beeps ]
[ cat cries sharply ]
Oh , my God . What are you doing ?
Stop that .
[ gunshot ]
[ cat meows ]
[ siren wails ]
[ alarm blares ]
[ second alarm chirps ]
[ horn beeps repeatedly ]
Drop the weapon ! Drop it now !
Get on the ground ! Put —
[ gunshot ]
Burning the midnight oil , Mr. Smith ?
Hey , now don 't forget to sign in .
[ gunshot ]
[ elevator dings ]
[ out of breath ] Hi .
[ helicopter flies overhead ]
[ dialing ]
[ rings ]
[ answering machine beeps ]
Harold , it 's Bateman , Patrick Bateman .
You 're my lawyer , so I think you should know
I 've killed a lot of people .
Some escort girls in the apartment uptown , uh ,
some homeless people , maybe five or ten , um ,
an NYU girl I met in Central Park .
I left her in a parking lot behind some doughnut shop .
I killed Bethany , my old girlfriend , with a nail gun ,
um , and some man —
some faggot with a dog .
Last week , I , uh , I killed another girl ...
with a chain saw .
[ sobbing ]
I had to .
She almost got away ,
and , uh ...
Someone else there . I can 't remember .
Maybe a model .
She 's dead , too ,
and , uh , Paul Allen .
I killed Paul Allen with an ax in the face .
His body is dissolving in a bathtub in Hell 's Kitchen .
I don 't want to leave anything out here .
I guess I 've killed maybe 20 people ,
maybe 40 , uh ...
I have tapes of a lot of it .
Some of the girls have seen the tapes .
I even , um ...
I ate some of their brains ...
and I tried to cook a little .
Tonight I , uh ...
[ laughs ]
I just had to kill a lot of people ,
and , um ...
I 'm not sure ...
I 'm gonna get away with it this time .
So , uh , I mean ...
Oh .
I guess ...
I 'm a pretty , uh ...
I mean , I guess I 'm a pretty sick guy .
So ...
if you get back tomorrow ,
I may show up at Harry 's Bar .
So , you know .
Keep your eyes open .
[ hangs up phone ]
[ sighs ]
[ people talking ]
Are you my 2 : 00 ?
No .
Can I help you ?
I 'm looking for ...
Paul Allen 's place .
Doesn 't he live here ?
No , he doesn 't .
You sure ?
You saw the ad in the Times ?
No .
Yeah . I mean , yeah .
In the Times .
There was no ad in the Times .
I think you should go now .
But I think ...
I want to know what happened here .
Don 't make any trouble , please .
I suggest you go .
Don 't come back .
I won 't .
Don 't worry .
[ rings ]
[ phone rings ]
Patrick Bateman 's office .
[ Patrick , panting ] Jean ?
- I need help . - Patrick , is that you ?
Jean , I 'm not —
[ snorts ]
Craig McDermott called .
Wants to meet you , David Van Patten , and Tim Bryce at Harry 's for drinks .
Oh , God .
What did you say , you dumb bitch ?
Patrick , I can 't hear you .
[ Patrick , laughing ] What am I doing ?
Where are you , Patrick ? What 's wrong ?
I don 't think I 'm gonna make it , Jean ,
to the , uh , office this afternoon .
Why ?
[ Patrick ] Just say no !
What is it , Patrick ? Are you all right ?
Stop sounding so fucking sad !
Jesus !
[ dial tone ]
[ Bryce ] Table for three .
[ McDermott ] Bateman , you look a little wild-eyed . Rough day at the office ?
Hey , look , Bryce is back , and he 's drinking mineral water .
He 's a changed man except he still can 't get a reservation
to save his life .
Why don 't you just try 150 Wooster ?
I 'm not going anywhere unless we have a reservation .
Le Cirque , Flamingo East , Oyster Bar .
Come on , faggots , let 's get a res .
[ Bryce ] Keep your shirt on .
Maybe lose the suspenders .
Need a reservation for 8 : 30 .
Excuse me , gentlemen .
Right back .
10 : 00 would not be any good , no .
Just fucking call them .
- Give me the phone . I 'll do it . - [ Bryce ] I 'll call ya back .
Face it . The Japanese will own most of this country
- by the end of the ' 90s . - [ laughing ] Shut up , Carnes .
They will not .
So , uh , Harold ,
did you get my message ?
Jesus , yes . That was hilarious .
- That was you , wasn 't it ? - Yeah , naturally .
Bateman killing Allen and the escort girls .
That 's fabulous . That 's rich .
What exactly do you mean ?
The message you left .
By the way , Davis , how 's Cynthia ?
You 're still seeing her , right ?
Wait , Harold . What do you mean ?
Excuse me . Nothing .
It 's good to see you .
Is that Edward Towers ?
Uh —
Davis .
I 'm not one to badmouth anyone .
Your joke was amusing ,
but come on , man .
You had one fatal flaw .
Bateman is such a dork .
Such a boring , spineless lightweight .
Now if you said Bryce or McDermott ...
Otherwise , it was amusing .
Now if you 'll excuse me , I really must be going .
Wait , um —
Stop .
[ whispering ] I did it , Carnes .
I killed him .
I 'm Patrick Bateman .
I chopped Allen 's fucking head off .
The whole message I left on your machine was true .
Excuse me .
I really must be going now .
No , listen .
Don 't you know who I am ?
I 'm not Davis .
I 'm Patrick Bateman .
We talk on the phone all the time .
Don 't you recognize me ?
You 're my lawyer .
Now , Carnes ...
listen .
Listen very , very carefully .
I killed Paul Allen ...
and I liked it .
I can 't make myself any clearer .
But that 's simply not possible .
And I don 't find this funny anymore .
It never was supposed to be .
- Why isn 't it possible ? - It 's just not .
Why not , you stupid bastard ?
Because I had dinner with Paul Allen twice in London ,
- just ten days ago . - No , you ...
didn 't .
Now , if you 'll excuse me .
[ crying ]
[ President Reagan ] We 've seen the results of that mistrust
in the form of lies , evasions , and mistakes .
We need to find a way to cooperate
while realizing foreign policy
can 't be run by committee .
And I believe there 's now the growing sense
that we can accomplish more by cooperating .
And , in the end ,
this may be the eventual blessing in disguise
to come out of the Iran-Contra mess .
How can he lie like that ?
[ Reagan ] ... 17 months left in this administration ...
- How can he pull that shit ? - What shit ?
Now where do we have reservations at ?
I mean , I 'm not really hungry ,
but I 'd like to have reservations someplace .
How can you be so fucking ...
I don 't know ...
cool about it ?
Some guys are just born cool , I guess .
[ laughs ]
Bateman ...
What are you so fucking zany about ?
[ laughing ] I 'm just a happy camper .
Rockin ' and a-rollin ' !
[ chuckles ] Oh , brother ! Look ,
he — he presents himself as this harmless old codger , but ...
inside ...
but inside ...
[ Bateman , thinking ] But inside doesn 't matter .
Inside ? Yes ? Inside ?
Believe it or not , Bryce , we 're actually listening to you .
Come on , Bateman ,
what do you think ?
Whatever .
Whose moronic idea was it to order dry beers ?
I need a scotch .
[ Reagan ] ... Judge Robert Bork .
When I named him to the U.S. Court of Appeals ,
the American Bar Association ...
[ Bateman ] There are no more barriers to cross .
All I have in common with the uncontrollable and the insane ,
the vicious and the evil ,
all the mayhem I have caused and my utter indifference toward it ,
I have now surpassed .
My pain is constant and sharp ,
and I do not hope for a better world for anyone .
In fact , I want my pain to be inflicted on others .
I want no one to escape .
But even after admitting this ,
there is no catharsis .
My punishment continues to elude me ,
and I gain no deeper knowledge of myself .
No new knowledge can be extracted from my telling .
This confession has meant nothing .
[ rock music playing ]
♪ Abracadoo ♪
♪ I lose you ♪
♪ We can 't avoid the clash ♪
♪ The big mistake ♪
♪ Now we 're gonna pay and pay ♪
♪ I guess you know ♪
♪ I never wanted anyone more than you ♪
♪ Lived all our best times ♪
♪ But I know you 'll hold Your head up high ♪
♪ There 's nothing we have to say ♪
♪ There 's nothing in our eyes ♪
♪ But there 's something in the air ♪
♪ There 's something I have to say ♪
♪ There 's something in the air ♪
[ new song ]
♪ Who feels it ♪
♪ Loves it ♪
♪ Who knows it ♪
♪ Shows it ♪
♪ Scratch it up , here comes my genius ♪
♪ Grandmaster Flash and the Furious ♪
♪ Nasty licks , they are serious ♪
♪ " The Message , " delirious ♪
♪ Do Boy 's a genius chameleon ♪
♪ Afrika Bambaataa holds dominion ♪
♪ Fugees on the scene Like a Fellini dream ♪
♪ Salvation 's here a la Al Green ♪
♪ Who feels it ♪
♪ Knows it ♪
♪ Who loves it ♪
♪ Shows it ♪
♪ Who feels it ♪
♪ Loves it ♪
♪ Who knows it ♪
♪ Shows it ♪
♪ Come on ♪
♪ So whatcha gonna do With a broken heart ? ♪
♪ Sip Cristal , burn up the chart ♪
♪ Whatcha gonna do When they put you down ? ♪
♪ Move to the tip , groove underground ♪
♪ Whatcha gonna do when You miss your mark ? ♪
♪ Chill out , choose a brand new start ♪
♪ How does it feel to be back on top ? ♪
♪ It 's good , uh-huh And you don 't stop ♪
♪ Who feels it ♪
♪ Knows it ♪
♪ Who loves it ♪
♪ Shows it ♪
♪ Who feels it ♪
♪ Loves it ♪
♪ Who knows it ... ♪
[ new song begins ]
♪ Yeah , I 've been watching me fall ♪
♪ For what seems like years ♪
♪ Watching me grow small ♪
♪ I watch me ♪
♪ Disappear ♪
♪ Slipping on out my ordinary world ♪
♪ Out my ordinary eyes ♪
♪ I 'm watching me ♪
♪ Scream ♪
♪ Fall ♪
[ new song begins ]
♪ Some girls got worries ♪
♪ So disconnect me ♪
♪ Mind and soul tormented ♪
♪ They 're so disconnected ♪
♪ But my kind of trouble ♪
♪ Is you ♪